<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Adventures in DH]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Adventures in DH]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/adventures-in-dh/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 01:04:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/adventures-in-dh/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 01:04:51 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Finding meaning, making meaning with text analysis.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Finding meaning, making meaning with text analysis.</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cdd9eace-0f62-4fea-b10a-11b60234ba87.jpg">,<p>In anthropology we often speak of the notion of webs of significance or webs of meaning. In essence, an mostly according to anthropologist Clifford Geertz, we all belong to different webs of meaning that we are part of constructing and upholding. Text analysis is like looking for those webs in individual or corpuses (sp?) of text.</p>,<p>In the readings for this section, I actually saw a couple of connections with code (the topic of our last section), most notably in Rockwell’s article, “What is Text Analysis, Really?”, when he writes about the creation of new texts as a result of the re-ordering of old ones to fit new narratives. The example he used was the bible, but I likened this to new programming languages, essentially taking parts of older and more established languages, and reconfiguring them to make new ones. With the advent of new text analysis tools, it is increasingly easier to find new ways of looking at texts and seeing patterns emerge that would otherwise be missed.</p>,<p>Another interesting phenomenon that arises from this, is that as content becomes increasingly digitized, with new content pretty much by default, there is a real interoperability to it, which makes it easier and easier to analyze with better and better tools. what i find wonderful about this is that suddenly text analysis becomes something that can be done at any time and therefore becomes more of a continuum rathe than discreet data points. Having said that, I am curious if there is much text analysis done on aggregated results of text analysis? what patterns would this meta analysis reveal, and would it align back to the original texts or become something on its own through iterations?</p>,<p>There is a dark path here however, in that the tools for analyzing the really big data sets are not very accessible to all researchers. If this is the case, it begs the question of whether current research that’s based on this data is inherently biased towards the limits of the hypotheses that generated this data to begin with? I see this as problematic, given that we are then left to make correlations based on assumptions.</p>,<p>All in all though, it is comforting to know that since no one has yet figured out the definitive way to do text analysis, we are all still happily iterating and learning from each other about different ways of finding meaning in an ever-growing body of knowledge.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/adventures-in-dh/finding-meaning-making-meaning-with-text-analysis/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d499842d-8e2a-49b6-b721-89b527cded91</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 01:03:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Hyde than Jekyll.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>More Hyde than Jekyll.</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/32b1a51c-d902-434e-a02e-745ad2d653ea.jpg" alt="Nothing is future-proof">,<p>I will say this, I tried. After many frustrating hours trying to get my Open Notebook with Jekyll to work on GitHub, I began to appreciate the nuance of the name. It was one of the most frustrating experiences I’d had in a long time.</p>,<p>The designer in me did not want to have a simple site that would just scroll endlessly. I also hated (and I do not use this word lightly) the fact that I could just not get the damn thing to do what I wanted it to do. As my thoughts began turning to Mr. Hyde, I recalled a lesson from my past.</p>,<p>There was point in my career at which I started to feel very unfocused. It was around 1999, and I had spent the better part of a year playing catch-up with the latest changes to HTML, trying to learn some Java, Javascript, LINGO, Flash, not to mention new features in adobe photoshop, illustrator and QuarkXpress. This was also the point in my career in which I saw that user experience (UX), although in its nascent stages, was going to be the future.</p>,<p>It was at this point that I made a conscious decision to excel at certain things, and stay aware of others. This was the lesson that I harkened back to. I am currently doing my masters degree in anthropology with a specialization in digital humanities, not to become a programmer, or to code, or to do any of those things. I am doing it to continue my journey of pulling back the curtain on culture, understand how others navigate the world, and translate that into designing better experiences with the information, products, and services that we come into contact with every day.</p>,<p>I will and do stay aware of this kind of technology, and am supportive of open source. However, I don’t believe anything is truly future-proof.</p>,<p>So, please, don’t take this as a revolt against best efforts to be exposed to something new. I was exposed to it, and I appreciate what it does, and that it has a place and a context. I just fundamentally do not believe that the tool is appropriate for me to do what I need to do, which is engaging with ideas, learning from them, and maybe even putting out some of my own.</p>,<p>This time, it’s about content, not context.</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/adventures-in-dh/more-hyde-than-jekyll/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1ae24ba5-8c8f-410d-bd17-32c64b60df47</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 13:23:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>